[The Unclouded Soul]
[Episode 25]
Support Admin Watch on
kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
So back then, the Heavenly Mother
used the Heart-Burning Incantation
and activated an array to reverse time.
It was to bring herself back
to the beginning of time
to find her younger self
to retrieve her primordial spirit
and restore her power.
Did she succeed?
I don't know.
This stone only
shows the Heavenly Mother
entering the array,
but nothing after that.
So
we don't know if she returned
or if she recovered her power.
We don't know.
Gosh...
The Time-Reversal Technique
is the only technique
no one dares to use lightly
despite it
not being a forbidden technique.
Once you use this technique,
those who enter
will return to their fetal state
without their memories or power
when traveling to the past.
In the Six Realms,
both humans and demons are no exception.
Only an extraordinary being
like the Heavenly Mother
can enter the array.
And even so, the outcome is uncertain.
Never mind.
It was just a desperate attempt anyway.
I'm a human and also a demon.
Which of the six realms do I belong to?
Right!
Xiao Yao is half human and half demon,
not belonging to any of the six realms.
She could enter the array
and return to the past
without her physical form being affected.
That's great!
If I go back,
how far back can I travel?
His Lordship's primordial spirit
was injured a hundred years ago.
If you want to retrieve the
true primordial spirit,
you must go back even further.
Then wouldn't I
be able to see His Lordship
as he was back then?
I wonder if he was more handsome then
or if he's more handsome now.
He was and is handsome at both times.
Stop fooling around.
How can I retrieve the primordial spirit?
Would I also be able to see
Princess Ning'an?
This is hardly the time
to be joking around.
I'm just curious.
Let's forget about
retrieving the primordial spirit.
Look at you,
bringing up exactly what you shouldn't.
My Lord!
Don't be angry!
Why is he angry?
My Lord.
Sending Xiao Yao back in time
might be the only way
to restore her spiritual power.
Even if that were the only way,
she can't go back, no matter what.
But we have to at least try.
What if she never comes back?
My Lord.
So what
if I never recover my power?
Don't mention this again.
My Lord, are you afraid
of facing the past,
or afraid of facing Xiao Yao
once she learns the truth about it?
Or perhaps
you fear that if Xiao Yao goes,
she may never return to this world.
[Residence of the Bulwark Duke]
The imperial decree has been issued.
War between the two races is inevitable.
This isn't about giving you a choice,
but offering you
a once-in-a-lifetime opportunity.
But now is not the right time for war.
Hong Ye has returned to Demons' Valley
with the ancient mirror fragment.
He also drove away Heiwu.
The demons must all be united now.
Meanwhile, the Feiyu Guard
has divided loyalties
and scattered minds.
Didn't you vow to eliminate all demons?
Why?
Now you have a legitimate reason to act,
yet you hesitate.
But not all demons
deserve to die.
You're afraid of hurting Xiao Yao,
aren't you?
Xiao Yao only has Hong Ye in her heart,
never you, not even a little.
You should face reality.
It's not just about Xiao Yao.
I, Bingzhu, have a heart and eyes.
I can see that
not every demon is evil.
You have a heart.
So you can connect
with those who have hearts.
I have no heart,
so I can only hide in this tiny space
day after day,
making you avoid me
as if I were a plague.
That's not what I meant.
How could you think that—
It's all my fault.
Why don't
you ask Tan'er what to do?
I've given you more than one chance
to get rid of me
to keep the Lu Pianpian you once knew.
But you can neither take action
nor let go.
Now there's no chance left.
Lu Pianpian doesn't exist anymore.
Only the Dreamshard Immortal does.
The situation now forces you
to lead the Feiyu Guard
into battle against the demons.
And you must win.
The Feiyu Guard
would like to see the Immortal Lord!
Hide yourself.
I'll hold them off.
Why have you come here?
Speak up.
The Feiyu Guard would like to ask
the Immortal Lord to replace our hearts.
We will serve the Immortal Lord.
-Go back!
-And spare no effort,
with absolute loyalty!
Spare no effort,
with absolute loyalty.
If your hearts are replaced,
you'll become demons.
Have you all
made up your minds?
I checked the Feiyu Guard records.
A colleague once received
a heart transplant from the Immortal Lord
and gained immense power,
able to fight a hundred enemies alone.
Now the Emperor has given us
a one-month deadline.
If we don't eliminate the demons,
all Feiyu Guards will be executed
and our families will also die.
Rather than waiting for death,
we might as well become demons ourselves.
We beg you to help us,
and save our lives.
Thank you, Immortal Lord.
[Cloud-Reaching Loyalty]
[Yunmeng Lake]
Demon Lord?
Sea Turtle Demon Lord?
Sea Turtle Demon Lord, are you there?
Demon Lord, are you slacking off?
Neglecting your duties, Demon Lord?
Demon Lord?
Demon Lord, over here!
Here!
I haven't been disturbed
for a thousand years.
Who are you?
I'm Heiwu.
I didn't mean to disturb
your peaceful rest.
What?
Peaceful rest?
[Sea Turtle]
Are you implying that I'm being lazy?
Please don't be angry,
Demon Lord!
It's just that the Demon King
is concerned for all demons.
Lately, he's been feeling anxious.
He fears a calamity might befall us.
And since Yunmeng Lake
is the most crucial demon seal,
he specifically sent me here
to check if the seal remains intact.
Should we go up and talk?
If there were any issues with the seal,
I would be the first to know.
Why would I need you to tell me?
I understand
the Demon King worries too much.
Demon Lord,
could you give me a hand?
Fine, fine.
Since you're just following orders.
He sank.
He sank!
Let's go.
Yes.
Come on, class is over.
All demons have
their subjects and characteristics listed,
so why doesn't Hong Ye have any?
He's a mighty Demon King...
Xiao Yao, let's go.
What are you doing?
Let me ask you something.
Have any of you been in human form
for over one hundred years?
The older ones
were mostly slaughtered.
What are you trying to find out
from a hundred years ago?
Well...
If the demon books don't have it,
human books might.
That's right!
I'll go check in the human realm.
Keep this a secret.
Mm-hmm.
Did I say something wrong?
No.
Right?
Yeah.
These creatures
are all suppressed by seals.
Look,
those ripples
and bubbles coming up
are caused by their breath.
The seals are very secure.
With me here,
even if sealed
for ten thousand more years,
nothing will go wrong.
Under what circumstances
would the seal loosen?
The seal is secure
and has never loosened.
Didn't you come to check
if the seal was secure?
Now that you've confirmed it's fine,
you may go back and report.
Please wait, Demon Lord.
His Lordship is too busy
to visit you in person,
so he specifically sent me
to bring you a gift.
[Ming] [Qing]
Qing Ming.
[Qing] [Ming]
Ming Qing.
This is truly excellent wine.
I brought this wine specifically
as it matches your namesake festival.
I've never tasted
wine with such a flavor before.
I wonder
how it was brewed?
Do you know about toad venom, Demon Lord?
Toad venom?
Yeah.
You're testing me?
Toad venom,
it clouds the mind
and causes hallucinations.
You're trying to poison me?
Wine is a poison that penetrates the gut,
but only drunkenness
can solve a thousand worries.
Ordinary wine
could never ease the troubles
of a Demon Lord like you.
Only this toad venom brew can.
I like it.
Good wine.
A toast to you, Demon Lord.
Cheers.
May I ask,
in this world,
is it only you
who can break this seal?
Actually,
I'm not the only one who can break it.
The Celestial Dragon,
Earth Emperor,
heart blood,
and also
the most important...
The most...
What is the most important, Demon Lord?
What is the Celestial Dragon?
And what is the Earth Emperor?
Why are you asking
such specific questions?
With this!
Along with Celestial Dragon,
which is Celestial Water.
The Earth Emperor
is Underground Fire.
Along with heart blood,
all flowing into this array.
May I ask...
Demon Lord?
Would you like another drink?
Demon Lord.
Celestial Water.
Underground Fire.
Heart blood.
Thank you, Demon Lord.
Celestial Water.
Underground Fire.
[Tianwei Gate]
The demons
have plagued our world for too long.
I bear the weight
of seven ancestral temples,
to safeguard peace throughout the realm.
I must do more than
merely preserve the imperial succession.
The late emperor established
the Feiyu Guard
to eliminate demons and monsters.
But our old methods of capturing demons
are no longer sufficient for the task.
A campaign against the demon realm
is now imperative!
Today,
the nine provinces are filled with vigor,
and the heavens stand ready.
I offer fine wine
to send off all our warriors.
May you all
be victorious in every battle
and return in triumph!
[Tianwei Gate]
Greetings, Exalted Immortal.
No, no!
If the Evil Demon appears,
it'll be a catastrophe!
This wine is perfect for today's occasion:
the Qingming Festival.
Demon Lord,
farewell.
Destroy the old world,
and establish a new order!
The demons
will be all mine now!
The world has fallen into chaos,
[Tianwei Gate]
and catastrophe is imminent.
If you can seize this opportunity
to eliminate the demons,
and establish extraordinary merit,
the immortals
will naturally grant you longevity.
I am willing to lead the charge
with all the might of Tiansheng Kingdom
to eliminate the demons!
As ruler of the kingdom,
you must not leave the imperial city.
If you move,
the realm will fall into chaos.
Then...
please guide us, Exalted Immortal,
how can we ensure victory for humanity?
Though immortals
cannot meddle in mortal affairs,
your sincerity is rare and commendable.
Give the military tally
to Bingzhu.
The army shall follow his commands,
and I have my ways to ensure victory.
Everything shall be
as the Exalted Immortal commands!
With the Exalted Immortal's assistance,
[Tianwei Gate]
you must seize this opportunity to settle
the thousand-year conflict
between humans and demons
with this final battle!
We will obey the royal command
and eliminate the demons!
Eliminate the demons!
[History Record]
[In the 248th year of the Tiansheng Era,]
[the great demon Hong Ye
brought calamity upon the mortal realm.]
[History Record]
In the 248th year of the Tiansheng Era,
the great demon Hong Ye
brought calamity upon the mortal realm.
He once attacked the imperial city,
injuring countless people.
Fortunately, Princess Ning'an
devised a strategy
to trap the demon
within an array.
Hong Ye fought desperately,
but Princess Ning'an,
with her noble heart,
sacrificed herself along with the demon,
ensuring peace for all living beings.
[Princess Ning'an]
What is this?
It's an auspicious sign from heaven,
with Buddha's light shining everywhere!
What nonsense are you talking about?
This is clearly an omen of disaster!
Nonsense!
The purple aura fills the sky,
it must be a sign of good fortune!
The true dragon appears and
the great demon emerges.
All living beings will suffer!
Suffering...
Suffering is upon us!
What do we do now?
My Lord.
The Demon Lord's token is broken.
Something terrible has happened
at Yunmeng Lake.
Legend says great demons
are sealed in Yunmeng Lake.
Could it be true?
Yes.
But in the ancient demon texts,
why is there no record of this?
The ancient great demons' power
is too strong.
They feared it might be
exploited
by ill-intentioned humans or demons.
So it was guarded by
Sea Turtle,
the longest-living of the demons.
Is their power
more powerful than My Lord?
Even if I had my power,
I may not be their match.
They?
There are three great demons
sealed in Yunmeng Lake.
It's really like the omen.
The tribulation of demons has come.
My Lord,
at such a critical moment,
are you still not going to use
the Time-Reversal Array?
Even if you can't retrieve
your primordial spirit,
at least
you can send Xiao Yao away
and protect her.
I am the one who broke the seal
and allowed you to see daylight again.
From now on, you must obey my commands
and help me become
the Monarch of All Demons.
With me, Qiong Qi, around,
[Qiong Qi]
who dares claim to be king?
Don't pollute my ears.
Are all demons dead?
[Ao Hen]
You're nothing but a stray beast,
yet you dare to claim kingship?
Ao Hen.
You're asking for death.
I'm afraid the one
who will die is you!
I've been asleep for so long,
[Teng She]
why all this talk of death
as soon as I wake up?
Put it out.
Be good.
Is there nothing else to do?
Don't stoop to his level.
Little bat?
Let me ask you.
You
released the three of us from the seal?
This kid isn't very old,
but his ambition is not small.
He wants to be the Monarch of All Demons.
Whoever dares to claim to be Demon King
will die quickly!
Did your clan's leader
never teach you this?
Little beast.
Let me ask you,
do you know how many years we were sealed?
You were sealed for a thousand years.
It was ten thousand years!
Ten thousand! Yes, ten thousand years!
I broke the seal
intending to give the world—
Kneel!
Back to you three.
You'd better be honest.
Don't use those bewitching words
to use us
to conquer the world for yourself.
I, Aohen, do know how to repay kindness.
If you know what's good for you,
we may help you a little.
Otherwise,
we'll first destroy your clan
then devour your primordial spirit.
Understand?
Yes, I understand.
I am useless.
The demons
are facing an unprecedented catastrophe.
I had no choice but to release—
To release...
the three of you
to eliminate the rebellious Demon King
and slaughter all humans.
Is there
a Demon King now?
Yes.
Who?
Hong Ye.
Hong Ye colluded with humans,
offering demons to humans for alchemy.
If you three don't intervene,
our demon race
is about to be slaughtered.
Where is Hong Ye?
I'll lead the way.
My goodness, you're finally back.
Quick, come with me.
What happened?
His Lordship has agreed to use
the Time-Reversal Technique.
Hurry, we'll be too late soon.
Is Princess Ning'an more powerful
than the Dreamshard Immortal?
Otherwise how could she have hurt Hong Ye?
Is Ning'an a bad person?
You all say I look like her.
Someone who looks like this
shouldn't be bad, right?
But...
I don't know the answer
to these questions
you're asking me either.
The Time-Reversal array
has never been activated before.
Besides, I've never gone back either.
Moreover,
with my power,
I can only activate the array
to send you in.
But as for when and where you'll end up,
I have no idea.
It's up to your own fate.
What if I'm sent to
an ancient volcanic crater?
That's unpredictable.
So do you still want to go?
Yes,
I'll go even if
there's only a glimmer of hope.
Then let's hurry.
Xiao Yao.
Remember this.
Fortune and misfortune are predestined.
If you face danger,
don't push yourself.
Yes.
Come here.
Let's begin.
Yes.
I will bring your primordial spirit back.
My Lord.
Don't lose focus.
Yes.
Xiao Yao,
come back safely.
Wait for me.
Xiao Ming.
Gather the demons
and go to Youning Cave.
Seal the entrance with a barrier.
My Lord.
Hurry!
My Lord!
Hong Ye?
We meet again.
It's been 10,000 years.
Today,
it's time to put an end to this.
Xiao Yao.
Who's there?
Since the Sky Stone guided you here,
it means you have a destiny to fulfill.
You are the Heavenly Mother?
How can I obtain
Hong Ye's primordial spirit?
All primordial spirits
are shaped by love and hate.
Only love and hate can hurt them.
To restore Hong Ye's spiritual power,
you need only collect a single drop
of his tear-essence.
How do I return after I get it?
To go is to return.
To come is to depart.
Xiao Yao.
Just remember—
you are, and will always be, yourself.
[100 years ago]
Where am I?
Is anyone there?
So beautiful.
Xiao Yao,
is that you?
A beauty that outshines the moon
and puts the flowers to shame—
it's you they talk about.
Then who am I now?
Who?
Your Highness.
It's time for lunch.
Your Highness...